Theofilus Hobba Pramono

Surakarta, Indonesia

(+62)831 7452 7699

in Theofilus Hobba Pramono

TheoHobba



Personal Profile

I graduated in astronomy and science communication with a scientific mindset and Python programming skills used to perform research with astronomy and/or communication backgrounds. Previous science communication and volunteering experiences helped me grow teamwork management, communication skills, and creativity, especially in developing science-related educational material.

I am currently interested in either working to develop educational materials for museums and informal educational programs or performing research on topics of exoplanets, light-curve analysis, or archaeoastronomy.

Education _

MS Leiden University, Astronomy and Science Communication and Society

Aug 2022 - Jul 2024

- GPA: 7.9/10.0 (Dutch grading system), equivalent to 3.78/4.00 (Indonesian grading system)
- Coursework: Star and Planet Formation, Exoplanets A: Interiors and Atmospheres, Advances in Data Mining, Informal Science Education, Scientific Narration and Vizualisation, Science Communication Product Development
- BS Institut Teknologi Bandung, Astronomy

Aug 2017 - Jul 2021

- GPA: 3.55/4.00 (Indonesian grading system)
- **Coursework:** Stellar Evolution, Stellar Physics, Observational Astronomy, Interacting Double Star Systems, Calendric System, Anthropology

Work Experience _____

Leiden University, Astronomy and Society Group Student Researcher Intern

- Performed research to analyze and explore present and prospective societal impacts of Indonesia's Timau Observatory
- Developed a strategic communication plan for Timau Observatory

Ditara Creative Enterprise, Freelance Content Writer and Editor

- Wrote astronomy contents to publish in Ditara's instagram account
- Edited and proofread Ditara astronomy contents

Tim Pembina Kompetisi Astronomi, Technical Team for Astronomy Observation

- Provided astronomical observation trainings for Indonesian Astronomy National Competition medalists in preparation for the International Astronomy and Astrophysics Olympiad
- Prepared questions, proctored, and juried the observation round of the Indonesian Astronomy National Competition

Leiden, The Netherlands Jan 2024 - Jul 2024

> Indonesia (Remote) Mar 2023 - Sep 2023

> Bandung, Indonesia (Hybrid) Jan 2021 - Dec 2022

Bosscha Observatory, Research Assistant Lembang, Indonesia Mar 2022 - Jul 2022 • Prepared and performed astronomy observations to acquire three open star clusters light curve data Bosscha Observatory, Public Outreach Staff Lembang, Indonesia Apr 2019 - Jul 2022 • Developed astronomy experiment modules for preschool, elementary, and junior high students · Moderated workshop group discussions for elementary and junior high school teach-• Created space-related topics presentation slides for teachers to use • Taught online astronomy classes for elementary and junior high school students Prepared and operated telescopes and managed crowds during public night visitation programs Prepared and operated one telescope for public to use during 2019 annular solar • Managed crowds and answered questions during the 50 years Moon landing commemoration program in 2019 Institut Teknologi Bandung, Astrophysics I Class Assistant Bandung, Indonesia Sep 2020 - Dec 2020 • Provided weekly tutorials for Astrophysics I undergraduate class students • Graded class assignments throughout the semester **Volunteer Experience** _ Leiden, The Netherlands **Leiden University**, Exoplanets 5 International Conference Student Volunteer Jun 2024 · Managed crowds and handed out microphones to asking participants during three of the five conference days Leiden University, Science Communication Student Conference Volunteer Staff Leiden, The Netherlands Dec 2023 - May 2024 • Worked in a team to develop conference's main outline, such as picking the main theme and subthemes, designing the conference, and arranging a rough schedule Welcomed and managed participants during the conference day Leiden University, Pale Blue Dot Carolina Link (PBD C-Link) Online Meeting Organizer Leiden, The Netherlands **Team Member** Oct 2023 - Feb 2024 · Sent emails to prospective participants, prepared some meeting presentation materials, set up meeting sessions, and post-edit the recorded main session Oude Sterrewacht, Open Day Volunteer Leiden, The Netherlands Oct 2023 · Welcomed and managed visitor flow during the annual Leiden Old Observatory Open Day Organizational Exprience ____ Himastron ITB Head of Science and Project Department

Timilada di Tib, meda di de	inerice and irroject bepartment	
 Led three divisions to 	provide Himastron ITB members	opportunities to deepen

their astronomy knowledge and skills and practice astronomy dissemination

ITB Student Orchestra, Head of Training Division

· Carried out trainings to improve theoretical and practical musical skills among members

Himastron ITB, Head of Pre-event and Exhibition

• Led a team to design and execute pre-event competition for Himastron ITB's biannual space week national event, Astara Ganesha

Bandung, Indonesia Jan 2020 - Jan 2021

Bandung, Indonesia May 2019 - Apr 2020

Bandung, Indonesia Jul 2019 - Oct 2019

Publications _

ASASSN-21js: A Multi-year Transit of a Ringed Disc

Aug 2024

T. H. Pramono, M. A. Kenworthy, R. van Boekel

10.1051/0004-6361/202450288

Research Projects _

Societal Impacts of Timau National Observatory, Indonesia: an Exploratory Study

Jan 2024 - Jul 2024

- Explored present and prospected societal impacts of Indonesia's Timau National Observatory to mitigate for possible problems and offer solutions through a properly developed strategic communication plan
- Tools Used: Atlas.ti

Follow Up of ASASSN-21js Light Curve

Oct 2022 - Jul 2023

github.com/TheoHobba/ASASSN-21js 2

- Cleaned and modelled the light curve of the star ASASSN-21js to explore possible scenarios of the star system's nature based on known theories
- · Tools Used: Python

Search for Exoplanets within 5 Southern Galactic Open Clusters

Mar 2022 - Jul 2022

- Prepared and performed astronomy observations to acquire three open star clusters light curve data
- Tools Used: Python, SAO Image DS9, Cartes du Ciel

Archaeoastronomy Studies of Sukuh and Cetho Temples in Central Java

Sep 2020 - Jun 2021

- Measured orientations of two ancient Javanese Hindi temples and statistically analyzed models of probable alignments between them and past positions of stellar objects to determine possible ancient societal and religious values
- Tools Used: R, Python

Language Proficiency _____

Bahasa Indonesia: Native

English: Full professional proficiency

Technologies _

Languages: Python, R, LTFX, Markdown

Technologies: Ms. Word, Ms. Excel, Ms. Powerpoint, Atlas.ti, GitHub, Jupyter Notebook, SAO Image DS9, Cartes du Ciel, IRAF